Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
Previously on
Star Trek: Strange New Worlds...
Commander Pelia.
this is Lieutenant Scott.
He needs your help.
- I know Scotty.
- Professor.
Is it not tradition
to make
a grand romantic gesture.
or have I again mistaken
how human relationships work?
I thought you and Christine
had decided
to give each other some space.
Indeed.
- Spock.
- Christine.
This is... Dr. Korby.
My date.
Captain.
we're picking up
that space radiation again.
Whatever this is
does not appear to be native
to the Blootar Nebula.
This is space. Lieutenant.
There's no such thing as...
native.
We're all children...
of the cosmos.
Cap. in the past hour. we have
had 14 more crew members report
to medbay
on account of melancholia.
I have seen this
only once before...
in the war.
Then we'll need a leg up.
But Captain. we're outside
of regulation space.
Don't lecture me
on jurisdiction. Lieutenant!
I wrote the book
on space... jurisdiction.
And I am known for my...
diction.
Now...
...get me... the Agonyans.
The Agonyans are extremely
dangerous space creatures.
You don't think I know that?!
Make the call. Lieutenant.
for the sake
of the Blootar Nebula and space.
Captain. I have the Agonyans
on the space-phone.
On viewer-screen.
Greetings
from the USS Adventure.
I am...
the captain of this vessel.
representing the whole of the
Alliance of Outer Space Planets.
I am Zipnop
of the Triathic Agonyan Empire.
All worship to us. small.
pathetic. human food-piles.
We scanned an unusual level
of radiation
in the Blootar Nebula.
Even though this is outside of
your empire's... jurisdiction.
That is a lie!
Spread by pathetic
but delicious humans.
And yet... Doctor.
have we not received
multiple cases of melancholia
- aboard this ship?
- We have. Cap.
And doesn't
melancholia only occur
when humans are exposed
to Agonyan radiation waves?
- True.
- Check and... mate.
Argh! You have figured out
our plan.
We may need your brain cells
to power our radiation.
but you will never stop us!
We can. and we will
because we must.
It is our duty...
as space explorers.
Not if we destroy you first.
I'd like to see you try.
But Captain. what if they can?
You humans are rich
with brain cells.
If you give them to us.
we will choose not
to destroy you.
You have
one minute to comply
with our wishes.
The Agonyans have put us
in an impossible situation.
There is... only one solution.
We can't give them
our brain cells.
We need it...
for many science reasons.
Captain. the Agonyans
are firing a series
of nuclear lasers at us.
Shields up! Brace for impact!
Fire photonos beams at them!
They're gone.
And so is...
- our brain cells.
- No!
What do we do?
First... we find the Agonyans...
...retrieve our... brain cells.
and then...
we get back our joy.
The last frontier.
This is the tale of
the USS Adventure
on its 84-month mission
as it treks across the furthest
reaches of the universe.
striving to find unknown life.
unexplained phenomena.
and new space destinations.
To go forward. to go beyond.
to go further and bolder
than anyone ever before.
Security Officer's Log.
Enterprise is about to pass
through the Kitolian Belt.
which centers on a neutron star.
But while Enterprise studies
the neutron star.
I've been assigned a separate
but equally important task.
Call it a dual mission.
You want me to...
play a game. sir?
Starfleet believes that
they have figured out a solution
to long-term.
faster-than-light travel.
Starships will soon be able
to go for more
than five years
without returning to Federation.
So. games and entertainment as
distraction and stress release.
Now the device we're going
to be testing is called
the "Re-creation Room"?
Holodeck. for short.
- Sounds better.
- Yeah.
Is this based
on battle simulators?
'Cause I-I've beaten
every one of those.
Why do you think we picked you?
But those simulators are usually
on starbases.
They take up huge amounts
of energy and processing power.
Can our ship actually handle it?
That's what we're here
to figure out.
Our orders are clear.
While Enterprise studies
the collapsing neutron star.
you're going
to test the holodeck.
Put it through its paces
under a real mission.
Show it could work under
genuine. rigorous circumstances.
How rigorous do you expect a
game on the holodeck to be. sir?
Well. it's a test. Lieutenant.
The kind of thing I'd do all the
time when I was a test pilot.
Which means.
you push it as hard as you can.
You told me
you needed a challenge.
You're welcome.
Am I interrupting?
In lieu of my normal
morning calisthenics.
I have elected
to continue dance training.
I have nearly
completed my routine.
Oh. don't stop on my account.
Computer. begin playlist:
Spock 19.
Tango.
Ambitious.
I just swung by to ask
about the field emitters
for the holodeck that
you've been fixing for Scotty?
Eyes up. Lieutenant.
You told me the eyes are
the anchor of the tango.
Are they not?
My diagnostics
are nearly complete.
I have realigned
the field emitters.
The holodeck should be
operational as soon
as you and Mr. Scott finish
designing a program for you.
- Thank you.
- Has the monitoring pin been much of a burden?
I actually forgot
I was wearing it.
That is a good thing.
It is best if it captures you
in a natural state.
so the holodeck can construct
the most realistic environment
for your specifications.
Speaking of. have you chosen
a subject for your simulation?
Not yet.
I am not well-versed
in human entertainment.
but violence and relaxation seem
to be popular.
Along with...
...romantic narratives.
Amelia.
Amelia Moon?
What the hell is that?
Detective stories
from Earth in the 1960s.
The-the captain of the ship
that rescued me
from the Gorn...
he-he gave me a copy.
and I became obsessed.
Amelia was an outsider.
but she always found herself
in the middle of a murder.
or a kidnapping.
or a heist gone wrong.
And she always got justice.
no matter what.
Let's just say...
she had an effect on me.
There are 112 of them
in the database.
That's plenty of material
to form the simulation.
Although. the computer might
have trouble keeping
the simulation running as it is.
Uh. Pelia's on shore leave.
so. you-you want
to call in Spock again?
It's nothing I can't handle.
I-I can balance
the processing needs
from the rest of the ship.
Although.
there is one wee wrinkle.
Uh. the holographic characters
need to be incredibly detailed
to pass muster.
The only bio-signatures
we have at that resolution
are from the transporter
pattern buffer.
We'll use their likenesses
to create holographic
interactive avatars.
Ready when you are. Lieutenant.
Using the Amelia Moon
novels as reference
and factoring in my skills
as an investigator.
create a new mystery that I will
find challenging to solve.
Spock. I...
I thought you'd finished
running diagnostics.
I wanted to ensure the
computer system is functioning
at normal parameters.
I appreciate your concern.
But. uh. don't tell Scotty.
He's been working very hard
on this.
Indeed. He is sensitive.
You may run and evaluate
the program on your command.
...run program.
I can practically smell
the ocean and the cigarettes.
It would be unwise to smoke
in the confines of the holodeck.
Or at all.
No. I just meant
it's-it's very. um...
Lifelike. Indeed.
I have spent so many hours
reading about Amelia. I just...
I just can't believe
I actually get to be her.
Well. as my ancestor.
Sir Arthur Conan Doyle would
write. "The game is afoot."
Thank you. Mr. Spock.
but this is
a single-player situation.
I am available.
should you decide
you need my assistance.
Good luck. Lieutenant.
Amelia Moon!
- Thank goodness you're here.
- Uhura.
Joni Gloss. We met briefly
when you handled
that Fox fiasco last November.
Saved my client's career.
and kept him out of San Quentin.
Now. follow me.
I'm the one who found the body.
Of course. I did.
I'm always the first to arrive.
And I have a rule in this town.
If you're on time. you're late.
And if you're late. you're dead.
In this case. literally.
Not by my hand. of course.
You'll put that in your record?
Only. you weren't the first
guest to arrive. were you?
One of them killed Tony.
I just don't know who.
That's why I called you.
I need you to solve this
before the cops show up.
They will arrest every one of us
just to sell the story to
the gossip rags. and then. poof.
before you know it.
half my clients. out of a job.
So. protect your clients.
Except the murderer. obviously.
I'm going to drop them.
Where's the body?
In there.
Staying honest.
I could barely look at him.
I'll stall the others
in the sitting room
while you go do
what it is you... do.
Got a light?
Fantastic.
Hollywood. California.
Mansions. movie stars.
and murder.
Strangulation.
But with what?
At 9:00 p.m. tonight.
Tony Hart.
head of Lomond Picture Studios
was strangled in his own home.
But with what?
And by whom?
And don't forget about
the "why."
Find your motive.
and you've got your killer.
Usually. a motive hides
quiet secrets hidden in shadows
and behind closed doors.
but I could see
this case had it all.
Passion. desperation.
jealousy. rage.
And as for the suspects.
you may recognize
some of the guests from
Lomond's television space
adventure hour.
The Last Frontier.
including the show's creator
TK Bellows
and former actress
turned producer Sunny Lupino.
The show's stars...
Adelaide Shaw.
Maxwell Saint and Lee Woods...
are also here.
along with Shaw's main squeeze.
Anthony MacBeau.
And you already met
power agent Joni Gloss.
Your host. Tony Hart. is dead.
and one of you murdered him.
Hold your horses.
Why would one of us
want to murder Hart?
Because your show was
about to be canceled.
Canceled?
But we're a hit.
Oh. Ratings.
Now. here's how this
is going to go.
No one is gonna
walk out of that door
or make any phone calls.
Even you. William Morris.
We're all gonna get real cozy
until we've worked this all out.
This can't be happening. To me.
What we know:
At 9:00 p.m. tonight.
someone strangled Tony Hart
with an unknown weapon
in his bedroom.
We know the killer
is in this room.
and we know the likely motive
is the cancelation
of The Last Frontier.
And the key to this puzzle...
...is as clear as glass.
What?
Wait. it wasn't...
it wasn't me.
Everyone knows your drink. pal.
I believe you.
Besides. you favor
a frostier shade of pink.
But this shade is classic.
Max Factor's Ruby Red.
released in 1955. and splashed
all over fashion magazines
on the iconic face of
model and pop star
Sunny Lupino.
What can I say.
I'm a trendsetter.
But that doesn't
make me a killer.
That doesn't.
But this does.
The Last Frontier was your
first project as a producer.
You fought to get it on the air.
leveraged your
relationships with the studio
and your ex-husband.
Bet your whole career on it.
Tony and I were divorced.
but we were still
very much invested
in each other's success.
You were a little more invested
than most. weren't you?
It's expensive to bring space
into American living rooms. so
you took a personal loan from...
...the mob.
But if the show was canceled.
you'd never be able
to pay it back. so...
...you killed Tony
to keep it on the air.
The only thing I know about
that man is that he's a fan.
He wanted an autograph.
Why the telelens. then?
I was having dinner
at Perino's with Johnny.
Carson. He was trying to
talk me into a project at NBC.
Tony was keeping tabs on me
to make sure
I wasn't being unfaithful.
To the studio.
But you're right.
I did invest my own money.
I just didn't
take it from the mob.
I sold the house.
Mine and Tony's first house.
Oh. but you love that house.
Until I convinced Alfred to
put me in Crows. I was just
another pair of lips.
But that Oscar opened doors.
And what did I use it for.
my own star vehicles?
No. When I heard TK's pitch
for The Last Frontier. I knew
it was special.
And you'd do anything
to save it.
You're damn right. I would.
I even came to Tony with a plan.
- But he refused.
- He agreed.
We were going over the details
when Maxwell Saint
interrupted us.
If you really want to know
what happened to Tony.
talk to him.
Oh. my God.
Lee? Is she dead?
You know I'm an actor.
not a doctor. right?
But. yeah. I mean. look at her.
She's obviously dead.
Poison.
- Scotty. you busy?
- A bit busy. yeah.
Your simulation is pulling
a wee bit more power
than expected. Why?
Base a holodeck
on a battle simulator
- and it's going to act like one.
- What does that mean?
Well. it's figured me out.
learned my moves.
- Just like an enemy opponent.
- Well. how can I change that?
No. I need a fresh eye.
someone who won't
see things like I do.
In book number 57.
Murder at the Paper Moon Inn.
Amelia Moon needed a partner.
Well. I'm afraid it can't be me
if you want the Enterprise
to continue running.
Oh. no. that's okay.
I think I might have the perfect
dance partner already.
Spock. thank you for coming.
I'm here to assist
in any way I can.
Though. may I ask.
if the holodeck
has defeated you.
why not just end the mission?
Look. Pike gave me
very clear orders:
Test the device
under rigorous circumstances.
Also. it didn't defeat me.
I leveled up
and then it
increased the difficulty.
Besides.
Amelia Moon doesn't give up
until she gets her man.
and neither do I.
I have briefed myself
on the case.
What was Detective Moon's
partner like?
- Proficient. I assume?
- He was a bumbling idiot.
- That does not seem useful.
- No.
You will be much more so.
Who's this guy?
Detective Spock.
He works with me.
I didn't know this was
a pajama party.
Hang on.
Did Central Casting send you?
What. with those ears?
Detective Spock
doesn't watch television.
So he's a communist?
More likely
one of those cinema snobs.
What does it matter?
The holo-Kirk seems
particularly agitated.
He should. he's number one
on my suspect list.
Thanks for coming so fast.
These fluctuations... here.
They're becoming more frequent.
We are six hours
from a collapsing star.
Minor surges are to be expected.
Everyone's pulling
an all-nighter.
I even recommended Pike
reinstate Ortegas.
And you trust her?
- I do.
- Auxiliary power
also seems to be having issues.
This seems beyond standard.
Don't worry. I've got
everything under control.
Wow. that is a sensory overload.
Oh. all normal.
all under control.
The omnidirectional
holo-diodes produce
a tremendous number of variables
to keep an eye on.
- Ah.
- Do you need a second set of eyes?
No. I've got it.
In my experience.
sometimes a second set of eyes
can be... detrimental.
I-I can handle it.
Okay. but I do need to sign off
on your engineering logs
before returning to work
on the neutron star.
Fingers crossed you improve
upon the haphazard example
set by your...
supervisor.
Yes. I'm familiar with. uh.
Pelia's infamous logs.
An eagle could go blind
from reading them.
Oh...
- Broken already?
- Oh. no. no.
Just a wee bug.
to be expected with
beta phase testing.
You know. a simulator this big
will automatically pull
processing power to compensate.
but. you know.
it's not a problem.
I'll just. um.
divert a little juice. Yeah.
La'An may be running this test.
but. uh.
you're the failsafe.
Understood. Loud and clear.
But. you know. I've got it.
Mr. Saint. did you kill
Tony Hart and Sunny Lupino?
Nope.
Did you?
Sonny said you and Tony
were fighting before he died.
A tiff. A row.
A tangle. maybe.
It's not even worth discussing.
It was jealousy.
Jealousy?
Your cuff.
There was an identical one
at the crime scene.
A little trinket
from Hart's secretary.
She likes me.
You were having an affair.
You caught me.
And Mr. Hart had an issue
with this?
Well. only because
he was having an affair
- with the same secretary.
- Hmm.
sounds complicated.
No. not really. It was casual.
You work closely with people.
and things happen.
You two must know how that goes.
What? We...
No. this-this is about you.
not... anyone else.
Look. I'm an actor.
I like drama.
but it's certainly
nothing to kill for.
And besides. I had already
convinced Hart that
it was over
between me and the secretary.
And how did you do that?
Me and Maxwell?
Absolutely 100% never.
You seem awfully heated
about that.
He's a chauvinistic egomaniac.
I can barely stand to be
on set with the guy.
Why would I go to bed with him?
Were you aware that
the show was being cancelled?
I heard whispers.
How did you feel about it?
Well.
my lines and my skirts have been
getting shorter and shorter
with every episode.
and the only person
who ever fought for
my character was Sunny.
And now she's dead. so...
Did you know that I was just 18
when I played
Hedda Gabler on the West End?
I'm good at what I do.
Detectives.
But all anyone seems
to care about is your love life.
Must be frustrating.
Yeah. it is.
But is it wrong to want love
and to be taken seriously
in my career?
So. why do you think there are
persistent rumors
about your affair
with Mr. Saint?
How did you feel
about Miss Lupino?
You mean. did I have a reason
to kill her?
No.
I admired her.
She couldn't settle
for being a work of art.
She wanted to make art.
Art means a lot to you.
It's everything.
If I can give a gift
to the world.
I want to help people unleash
the artistic beast
inside of them.
How does one
"unleash the artistic beast"?
I've been doing
an artists salon.
Lee probably told you about it.
What goes on
at an artists salon?
Mac plays guitar.
Others sing. paint.
- And you?
- Lee writes.
She's been writing
a screenplay. actually.
- A movie.
- A screenplay?
Why?
Mac told you that?
A western set in the Dakotas.
There was a script
in the victim's room.
about the Dakotas.
Who else knew about this?
Guilty conscience got you running?
More like a weak stomach.
Must be hard to watch something
you've poured so much into
just disappear.
It's not my
favorite feeling. no.
But the ratings were too low
to warrant a season two?
Our fanbase is small.
but it's quite passionate.
Were you threatened
by the Western motion picture
Miss Woods wrote?
Lee wrote another Western?
Good for her.
She'll never tire
of that dying genre.
So. you knew about the script?
You weren't jealous?
What about the cancellation?
Did you know about that. too?
Is that why you ripped up
your contract? Out of anger?
Do you know what they say about
a show after its first season?
No. What do they say?
Practically writes itself.
Hart ripped up that contract.
not me.
He was actually
doing me a favor.
You wanted to leave the show?
Warners has the rights
to a book I've been chasing.
They're even gonna
let me direct.
Yeah. I-I-I love our show.
but movies...
That's how you change
hearts and minds. kids.
So. you're happy the show
was being canceled?
Oh. Detective.
I'm a writer.
I'm never happy about anything.
But I didn't kill anyone.
They all worked together.
yet allowed their emotions
to jeopardize
the very work
that they all shared.
What is that?
Lee Woods's script.
I knew something
was off about it.
Look. no title page.
But why?
Perhaps to hide the connection
to the writer.
No. no. no. not from Bellows.
He didn't even care.
No.
What if Lee's not the one
who removed it?
La'An...
The chandelier
appears to have been
purposefully cut to harm us.
To stop us
because we're close.
The screenplay
doesn't have a title page
because it was stolen.
Hart stole Lee's script and was
going to credit someone else.
probably a man. because that
happened all the time back then.
So she killed him for it.
There is a more pressing matter.
Blood?
Well. I-I thought the holodeck
had safety protocols.
Perhaps they are malfunctioning.
We should get out of here.
not risk anything else.
Computer. end program.
Mr. Scott. please end program.
Computer. arch.
So...
we can't shut it off.
the program
could actually hurt us.
and we can't get out.
Indeed.
Uh...
Lieutenant Scott.
are you looking for me?
Say I've got this hypothetical
communications problem.
could you advise me
on this problem that. again.
you know.
it's not a real problem.
in the traditional sense
of the word "problem."
- It's...
- I think I followed that.
In the highly unlikely event
that I were to have lost
all contact with La'An
inside the holodeck.
what would you advise?
Uh... Well. if comms failed.
I'd bypass local subprocessors
and patch directly
into the optical data network.
Yeah. Imagine
in this hypothetical.
like. I've already done that.
multiple times.
Hypothetically.
I'd shut the simulation down.
- Uh...
- Which. I'm assuming.
you've already.
hypothetically. done.
Scotty. are you telling me La'An
is trapped in the holodeck?
Have you tried
knocking on the door?
Or simply blowing it off?
The holodeck is a complex
balance of forcefields.
tractor beams.
and precision-guided diodes.
all hardwired in.
So. blowing it up would crash
our entire computer system.
Permanently.
Per my calculations.
the only way
to unlock the program
is for the lieutenant
to complete it.
but she's unaware of this.
What does completing it entail?
Solving a murder mystery
set in 1969 Hollywood.
I'm on it.
- Thank you. Ensign.
- Yeah.
Eh. oh. you-you know
that wasn't all hypothetical?
Yeah. I caught on
almost immediately.
Okay.
Unfortunately. I was unable
to access the panel
while in the simulation.
I still can't reach Scotty
over comms
or anyone on the ship.
So. we have a computer problem
and a communications problem.
We also have a murderer problem.
If the killer comes after us.
we could actually die in here.
So maybe the only way to survive
is to catch the murderer.
Which means...
we're going to go
solve this mystery.
I-I just...
can't believe
you wanted off the show.
You also wanted off the show.
You know what I think?
I think you hate me.
and you hate the fact
that I gave you the best job
that you're ever gonna have.
Are you threatening me?
Did you all hear that?
TK threatened me!
He tells no lies.
What would you know?
You're only here
as Adelaide's escape hatch.
What is that supposed to mean?
Audiences don't like you.
At least I can deliver
a line realistically.
It's called acting.
- Oh.
- And you know
what's not realistic?
A lady first officer.
Face it.
You knew your days were limited.
That's why you agreed to marry
Mick Bowie over here.
so you could disappear on tour
as his groupie
and nobody would notice
that your career was dead!
Everyone shut up. now!
Right.
Where is Lee Woods?
And who is this guy?
She's dead.
Joni Gloss.
It's not what it looks like.
I was just looking for a light.
She was dead when I found her.
You had quite a bit
of cash to lose
from the cancelation of
The Last Frontier. didn't you?
I had three clients
on that show. You do the math.
But I didn't kill Tony Hart.
though I wish I had.
And why is that?
Because canceling
The Last Frontier
is the stupidest thing
Tony's ever done.
Do you realize how rare
a show like this is?
TK wanted to give audiences
a digestible reflection
of their own world
through the lens of fantasy.
Social commentary
with rubber masks
and buried metaphors.
You know. science fiction.
And the studio did not agree
with this vision?
They were more...
cautious.
Didn't want to "make waves."
The cowards.
TK wanted Frontier
to take our rotten world.
with its warts and injustices.
and give audiences
something better.
And all of that
with weekly space adventures?
You don't find
the idea inspiring?
You don't think some kid out
there is going to see this show
and spend the rest of their life
searching the stars?
You don't think a person
can love a piece of art
or music or a story so much
that it heals them?
Shows them parts of themselves
they'd never even seen before?
And give them hope?
Um...
Well. no. of-of course I do.
A show like this
could've gone on forever.
Given generations
of fans a place
to feel seen. to belong.
something to believe in again.
no matter who they were
or where they came from.
But you can't do any of that
without a season two.
Finally. a light.
A fake fire?
Tony had impeccable
taste in film.
but his sense of decor
is just tragic.
What's inside the fireplace?
Celluloid film.
Discontinued
in the 22nd century.
many say to the detriment
of cinema.
I think this is
the murder weapon.
But it's also a recording.
There's something on this film
the killer wanted to destroy.
but made the same mistake
Joni did.
Spock. we have to see
what's on this.
All right. neutron star collapse
is imminent.
Uhura. are scanners
receiving data?
Right on time. sir.
Captain. I'm detecting
a gamma burst
heading into our flight path.
It's heavier energy
than expected.
The sensors are overloading.
Shields up.
Let's go to yellow alert.
Ortegas. take us down.
Steer as clear as you can.
I'd like to.
but we just had
a massive power drain.
Engines aren't responding.
Neither are shields.
Bridge to Science Lab.
Mr. Scott.
what's happening to our system?
Well. it seems the holodeck
is pulling a wee bit more power
than I'd anticipated.
Then shut it down.
We have a situation on the
bridge. and I need power. now.
Yeah. it's not quite that easy. sir.
- Um...
- Red alert.
Mr. Scott.
without engine power.
we are going to fly head-first
into a massive gamma-ray burst.
and we are not
going to survive it.
Mr. Scott. I need a solution.
Uh... I can manually
reroute power to you
in small increments.
That should give you something.
Do it. Do it now.
You've got roughly
30 seconds of acceleration.
Can you make that work?
I do like a good challenge.
We're through.
Let's hope
there isn't another one.
Mr. Scott. I'd like to talk
to Lieutenant Noonien-Singh.
Uh. let me see if I can get her.
Let's say I figured out a way
to contact La'An.
Hypothetically.
Then you'd be
my hypothetical hero.
I think you can't get through
in a conventional way
because the AI is blocking out
all comms
that don't come
from the simulation.
It's refusing
to let her talk to anyone
who's not part of the program.
It's-it's... it's evolving.
So you need to convince it
you're a hologram. too.
Oh.
I wrote the book
on space jurisdiction.
and I am known...
...for my... diction.
Now...
get me... the Agonyans.
The Agonyans?
- Oh... cut!
- What?
Keep rolling. Keep rolling.
- Okay.
- Was that too much? I-I...
I thought it was great.
- I completely felt it.
- Okay. okay. okay. okay.
Okay. Quiet on the set.
Quiet on the set.
What's the problem now?
Oh. where do I even start? Uh.
maybe you could try
delivering the line
like an actual human being
for once?
Oh.
Well. maybe
if you wrote a line...
- Uh-huh. Oh.
- ...worth delivering. I could try to.
- Uh-huh.
- What is this scene even about?
I thought it was about capitalism.
Big surprise.
You didn't understand
the script.
Again.
Does no one here care
about my vision?
Uh. sir?
- What?!
- Uh. you...
There's a call. Um...
Not a good time.
What? I...
You can't do that. I-I...
I am the show. You c...
I...
You'll regret this.
La'An? La'An?
La'An. I don't know
if you'll see this.
but it was my only chance
of getting a message to you.
The holodeck is pulling
all computer
processing power
from the rest of the ship.
The only way to stop it is
to end the program. which means
you have to solve the mystery.
Wait. If we're pulling
all processing power.
that includes shields.
navigation. life support.
They could die.
We could all die.
An accurate assessment.
An accurate asse...
How are you not more concerned?
These are our friends.
our lives.
You asked me to remain detached.
I am merely doing
as you requested.
We now know that Bellows did
indeed care very much
about the cancellation.
Yep. That gives him motive.
and he had an opportunity.
But he had no reason
to kill Woods or Lupino.
She didn't cancel the show.
She would have done
anything to save it.
That's true.
Including firing me.
You know.
for such a smart detective.
you're awfully stupid.
They weren't canceling us.
They were replacing me.
On my own show.
Perhaps we should sit down
and calmly discuss this.
I came here calm. I came here
to ask for my job back.
Do you have any idea
how humiliating that is?
And when he said no.
that's when you...
I didn't kill anybody!
- Then put the gun down.
- Hmm?
You could actually
hurt someone in here.
Th-This isn't a game anymore.
This was never a game.
This is my career.
And I'm not putting the gun down
because I'm not the killer.
But someone else here is.
Me?
- Mm.
- I was brought here
- to solve this case.
- I know.
Amelia Moon.
the great detective.
Death just seems
to follow her wherever she goes.
No. this is crazy. I...
And your strange friend
in his odd clothes.
so devoid of emotion.
Always watching.
studying.
Hey. wait a minute.
Did the network send you?
Are you my replacement?
No! You idiot!
He was just here to help me!
I-I didn't. I didn't.
Spock? Spock?
I'm okay.
Oh. thank God.
Wh...
What is it?
It's you.
You're the killer.
You poisoned Lupino's cup
when you were
"running diagnostics."
You sabotaged the chandelier.
then saved me from it.
And then...
you killed Woods.
A novel theory.
but I have no motive.
I am simply your colleague.
assisting you with a case.
You're not even a part
of this story.
I brought you here.
Because you made me
bring you here.
You're not my colleague.
You're a hologram.
You have been since the moment
I walked into the holodeck.
I asked the computer
for a mystery made for me.
and it gave me you.
because. well.
it watched me earlier
with the real Spock. and...
...it knew
I'd never suspect him.
Bravo.
Lieutenant La'An Noonien-Singh.
You have solved the mystery.
Oh.
Computer...
...end program?
While holodeck technology
certainly holds promise.
the risks
outweigh the potential benefits.
We do not recommend
the device be installed
on active ships... at this time.
How about we recommend
that it be locked
in a box
deep underground somewhere?
Well. if I could just make
one wee. tiny addendum.
It-it just needs
a dedicated server room
- and power source that...
- Mm.
Include it in the report.
but as a footnote.
In small print.
Lieutenant?
Do you know
how many crew we have on board?
Uh...
- Uh...
- 203.
Specifically. 203 of the finest
Starfleet has to offer.
There is never any reason
to do something alone
when you need help.
Yeah. but what if there is?
About a week before my last ship
ran into the Gorn.
I was building a sensor array.
I thought I saw some anomalies.
but I didn't have time
to finish it.
My CO said she would.
but she didn't. and then we...
What happened on the Stardiver
wasn't your fault.
What we do here is hard.
and sometimes bad things happen.
But this crew is a team.
Knowing when to ask for help
isn't a weakness.
It's a strength.
One the captain and I
value very highly.
Thank you for agreeing to finish
our lesson from earlier.
Of course.
Computer.
begin playlist: Spock 21.
So I take it the holodeck
mystery test was not
to your satisfaction.
Well. I requested
a solo mystery.
yet the holodeck led me
to believe I needed a partner.
You.
It misunderstood your prompt?
That. I think
it understood perfectly.
I just didn't take into account
that the holodeck knew me
better than I realized.
It gave me a suspect
I never anticipated.
Interesting technology.
How did you deduce this twist?
I didn't at first.
I was looking for clues
in all the wrong places.
But now I understand the puzzle
it built for me.
And what was that?
It created a holographic
version of you
that was clear-headed. logical.
Cold.
Words that have been used
to describe me.
But I...
I know you.
I know the feel
of your arms when we dance.
I... know the way
we look into each other's eyes.
He didn't look at me like that.
Or perhaps
I've misread the situation.
Earlier today...
I wondered if it was I
who had misunderstood.
Because for a moment.
I thought that you wanted...
And... did you also want?
We will eat the human food-pies!
Is it... is it pies. or piles?
- It's piles.
- Pies?
Left.
And back. Right. right. right.
right. right. right.
- And right!
- Oh.
How's this?
How about this?
- Goddamn it!
- Costumes!
You guys. is it "nebula"?
Whoa!
- Then we'll need a leg up.
- That's my line!
- I thought I had the leg bit.
- Line?
- What? Why would you have the leg bit?
I-I don't know.
I thought I had the leg bit.
Well. it's clearly my line!
It's a captain's line.
Why would she have the leg bit?
It's my line.
Yeah.
We're waiting on sound.
Red leather. yellow leather.
Ah. ah. ah. ah.
Hey.
I've lost her.
I've lost her!
Jesus Christ. I was trying
to get my leg over.
Can... this chair...
Can someone fix the chair?
Please?
I'm... I w...
I can't work like...
Open the door.
Help. Help!
- Whoa. whoa. there!
- Yeah. I got you.
Captioning sponsored by CBS
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org